scienceofsciencepolicy.net 2011-07-10

# Privacy Policy | Science of Science Policy

## General Statement

This Privacy Policy ("Privacy Policy") discloses the privacy practices for the Science of Science Policy community (collectively, "SoSP ") with regard to use of the Web site (www.scienceofsciencepolicy.net) ("Site" or "Sites"). SoSP is committed to the privacy of its users ("User" or "Users"). SoSP hereby notifies Users of the following:

  1. What personally identifiable information is collected from Users through this Site. 
  2. How the information is used. 
  3. How the information may be shared. 
  4. How the information is protected. 
  5. How Users can request corrections to inaccuracies in the information. 
  6. What SoSP's contact address is for privacy questions. 

### 1\. INFORMATION COLLECTED

**a. Information collection and use**

SoSP is the sole owner of the information collected on this Site. SoSP will not sell, share, transfer or rent any personal information to others in ways different from what is disclosed in this Privacy Policy statement and in the Terms of Use. SoSP collects and displays information from Users on the Profile and Registration pages ("Profile pages") on this Site.

**b. Registration**

During the collection of information at the Profile pages on the Site, Users are required to give contact information (such as name, institutional affiliations, e-mail address, and the like). An e-mail address is used to confirm the User's identity. An e-mail address is also used to contact Users about the materials and information on the Site. When the Site requests a user identity, the purpose of the inquiry is clearly indicated. Any of the professional information collected may be authenticated against a third-party provider.

**c. Personal Profile**

Once a registered participant, the User may provide additional information in his or her personal profile describing credentials, professional experiences, academic background, biography, and the like. The User's personal profile shall be available for viewing by other registered participants of SoSP and will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. Providing additional information in the User's personal profile beyond what is required at registration is entirely optional and can be altered or removed by the User at any time.

**d. IP Addresses**

Every computer connected to the Internet is given a domain name and a set of numbers that serve as that computer's Internet Protocol or "IP" address. When the User requests a page from any page within the Site, our Web servers automatically recognize the domain name and IP address. The domain name and IP address reveal nothing personal about the User other than the IP address from which the Site has been accessed.

**e. Opt Out Procedures**

Upon initial communication from SoSP, Users may opt-out of receiving further communications from SoSP. To be completely removed from the SoSP mailing list, a User may contact [sospwebsite@nsf.gov](mailto:sospwebsite@nsf.gov "SOSP@ida.org"). If using an e-mail forwarding service or other similar service, please make sure to include the correct e-mail address or addresses.

### 2\. INFORMATION USE

**a. Cookies**

A cookie is a small piece of data that is sent to a User's browser from a Web server and stored on a User's computer's hard drive. A cookie cannot read data off a User's hard disk or read cookie files created by other sites. Use of a cookie is in no way linked to any personally identifiable information while on the Site. Once a User closes his or her browser, the cookie simply terminates. For instance, by setting a cookie on the Site, the User would not have to log in a password more than once, thereby saving time while on the Site. A User can choose whether to accept cookies by changing the settings of the browser used. A User can set the browser to refuse all cookies or allow the browser to show when a cookie is being sent. If cookies are rejected on the Site, a User may still be able to use the Site, but use may be limited to certain minimal function or to certain areas of the Site. Some of SoSP business partners may use cookies on the Site. However, SoSP has no access to or control over these cookies. SoSP and its business partners may use cookies to better personalize the content, banners, and promotions that a User sees on the Site.

**b. Log Files**

SoSP may use IP addresses to analyze trends, administer the Site, track user movement, and gather broad demographic information for aggregate use.

**c. Personal Profile**

The information the User provides on his or her SoSP profile will be available to other SoSP community members and members of the public depending on the security settings each User chooses when designing his or her own profile. A User's personal profile shall be available for viewing by other registered participants of SoSP and will be considered non-confidential and non-proprietary. Depending upon the security settings and interests, SoSP may contact a User regarding upcoming events, funding announcements, job opportunities, and other items that may be of interest to the User. Should a User wish to opt out of these announcements, the User can do so by changing his or her profile's security settings.

### 3\. INFORMATION SHARING

**a. Sharing**

SoSP may share aggregated demographic information with SoSP's partners. This information is not linked to any personal information that can identify any individual person. SoSP shall not be liable for the transfer of any personal identification information resulting from loss or distribution of data, the delineation or corruption of storage media, power failures, natural phenomena, acts of vandalism, sabotage, terrorism, or any other event beyond SoSP's control.

**b. Consulting**

SoSP may partner with another party to provide specific services. When a User signs up for these services, SoSP may share names or other contact information necessary for the third party to provide these services. Per SoSP's contractual arrangements, these parties are not allowed to use personally identifiable information except for the explicit purpose of providing these services.

**c. Spam**

SoSP maintains a strict "No-Spam" policy, which means that SoSP does not intend to sell, rent, or otherwise give a User's e-mail address to a third party without the User's specific consent.

**d. Forums, Discussion Boards and Blog Comments**

When a User participates in a www.scienceofsciencepolicy.net Forum, including, but not limited to, Forums, Discussion Boards, and Blog Comments, the User's name and IP address may be recorded for purposes of maintaining the account within the Forums, and preventing abuses of the Forums (see Forum or online community rules for more details). This information is not used to personally identify a User outside the SoSP community. In order to diffuse the information in the Site's Forums to a wider audience, SoSP may, from time to time, collect some of its user postings and group them together to use in a specific publication, print, electronic mailing, or other public dissemination. When user postings are used in this fashion, they may be edited to fit with the general content of the publication being prepared. It is important to remember that whenever a User voluntarily discloses personal information in a forum, through e-mail or elsewhere, that information can be collected and used by others. If a User's personal information is accessible to the public, a User may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return. Ultimately, the User is solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of his or her personal information. A User may participate in any Forums offered through SoSP, but the User agrees not to post any material content that (i) is defamatory, libelous, obscene, indecent, abusive, threatening to others, or in violation of any law; or (ii) infringes the copyright, trademark right, or other intellectual property right, of any third party. Each User is solely responsible for all content that is posted by him or her on any Forum of SoSP. The User agrees to indemnify SoSP and its officers and employees from and against all liabilities, judgments, damages, and costs (including attorney's fees) incurred by him or her which arise out of or are related to the content that the User posts. Forums are intended only for the personal use of SoSP subscribers and may not be used for commercial purposes or for organized political activity.

### 4\. INFORMATION PROTECTION

**a. Confidentiality and Security**

SoSP takes all necessary precautions to protect Users' personal information both online and offline. No administrator at SoSP will have knowledge of a User's password. It is important for each User to protect against unauthorized access to his or her password and computer. Be sure to log off from SoSP when finished using a shared computer to access the Site. SoSP also protects a User's personal information offline. Access to a User's personal information is limited to employees who SoSP reasonably believes will need that information to provide services to the User. However, SoSP is not responsible for the confidentiality, security, or distribution of a User's own personal information by SoSP partners and third parties outside the scope of its agreement with such partners and third parties.

**b. Links**

The Sites at www.scienceofsciencepolicy.net may contain links to other sites. The linked sites are not necessarily under the control of SoSP. Please be aware that SoSP is not responsible for the privacy practices of such other sites. SoSP encourages its Users to be aware when they leave this Site and to read the privacy policies of each and every Web site that collects personally identifiable information. If a User decides to access any of the third-party sites linked to this Site, the User does this entirely at his or her own risk. Any links to any partner of the Site is the responsibility of the linking party, and SoSP shall not be responsible for notification of any change in name or location of any information on the Site.

### 5\. REQUESTING CORRECTIONS TO INFORMATION

**a. Correcting/Updating Personal Information**

SoSP encourages Users to maintain current profiles by correcting and updating information as necessary.  Users can update or remove their profiles by accessing the Profile pages of the Site. Please endeavor to correct, update, and, where necessary, remove personal data as it changes.

**b. Notification of Changes**

If SoSP decides to change the Privacy Policy for this Site, SoSP will post those changes on www.scienceofsciencepolicy.net so each User is aware of what information SoSP collects, how SoSP uses it, and under what circumstances, if any, SoSP discloses it. If SoSP decides to use personally identifiable information in a manner different from that stated at the time it was collected, SoSP will notify Users by way of e-mail. If a User has provided personally identifiable information before the changes in SoSP's Privacy Policy, the User will have a choice as to whether or not SoSP uses that information in the changed manner. If the User chooses that SoSP not use personally identifiable information in accordance with the new privacy policy, SoSP will use information in accordance with the privacy policy under which the information was originally collected.

**c. Site and Service Updates**

As necessary, SoSP may send the User site and service announcement updates. The User is not able to unsubscribe from service announcements, which contain important information about the Site. SoSP communicates via e-mail with each User to provide requested services and to resolve issues relating to User accounts.

**d. Consent to This Policy**

The Terms of Use Agreement is incorporated herein by reference in its entirety.

### 6\. CONTACTING SoSP

Contact SoSP by e-mail or mail with questions about this policy or SoSP's information collection, use, and disclosure practices.

Science of Science Policy (SoSP)  
1899 Pennsylvania Avenue, Suite 520  
Washington, D.C. 20006

SoSP tries to respond promptly to requests, questions, or concerns Users may have regarding our use of personal information. Except where required by law, SoSP cannot ensure a response to questions or comments regarding topics unrelated to this policy or SoSP's privacy practices.
